Previously, we saw how TabNavigator allows
之前我们看到 TabNavigator 使我们能够
us to navigate between different tabs in our application.
在应用中的不同标签页之间导航
And now, we're going to see how StackNavigator allows us to drill deeper
现在 我们将了解 StackNavigator 如何使我们能够
into our route hierarchy and also have a nice little right to the left transition there.
转到深层次的路径层级结构 并且能够从左到右地过渡
So what we'll do is just like we did with TabNavigator.
就像 TabNavigator 一样
Let's go down here and we will create,
我们转到这里
let's just call it Stack.
输入 Stack
And we are going to invoke
调用 StackNavigator
StackNavigator and then we are going to have two different routes.
我们将设置两种不同的路径
The first one is going to be this home component.
第一个是这个 Home 组件
And you'll notice what we're rendering here is the text, Home View.
我们在这里渲染的是文本“HOME VIEW”
And then we want to render a button that when we click on it is going to
然后我们想渲染一个按钮 当我们点击该按钮时
take us to the Dashboard View which is just this component right here.
能够转到 Dashboard 视图 也就是这个视图
So what we will do, exactly like we did with TabNavigator.
和 TabNavigator 完全一样
We will say, Home and what we want to render is the Home Component.
在这里输入 Home 我们要渲染的是 Home 组件
And then we will also have a Dashboard route and the screen we will use is Dashboard.
然后设置 Dashboard 路径 screen 将为 Dashboard
So that looks good.
看起来不错
Now, what we need to do is just render our StatComponent.
现在渲染 Stack 组件
And now, if we look at our app,
看看应用效果
you'll notice that we have both our home screen showing here.
这是两个主屏幕
But if we click on this button,
但是点击这个按钮后
obviously nothing happens because we haven't tied up
很明显什么也没发生
anything to our TouchableOpacity component.
因为我们尚未将任何内容连接到 TouchableOpacity 组件
So what we can do and you'll notice we're being passed this Navigation Prop,
我们在这里传入了这个 Navigation 属性
we can come in here and we can say when the user presses on this component,
在这里设置为：当用户点击此组件时
what we want to do is we want to say navigation.navigate,
我们将输入 navigation.navigate
and where we want to go is the Dashboard Component.
并转到 Dashboard 组件
So now, what will happen is when I hit two Dashboard,
现在 当我点击“To Dashboard”按钮时
notice we get taken to a brand new route here.
我们转到了新的页面
And what's nice again about React Navigation is it
React Navigation 的好处是
takes into account the different platform differences.
它会考虑不同平台具备的特性
So the animation on Android is a little different than the animation on iOS.
因此 Android 上的动画效果与 iOS 上的有所不同
And so now what I want to do is there's some things we can do with the header up
我们可以在这里的标题部分进行设置
here and we can go ahead and specify those in our Navigations object right here.
我们可以在这里的 NavigationOptions 对象中进行设置
So I want to have a title on the home screen and it's just going to say, Home.
我希望在主屏幕上显示一个标题“Home”
So now you'll notice that we have Home up here.
现在这里出现了 Home 字样
And on the Dashboard screen,
我们在 Dashboard 屏幕上
we'll also have some Navigation options.
也会设置一些 navigationOptions
Title will be Dashboard.
title 将为 Dashboard
But now, let's go ahead and get a little bit fancy.
现在设置一些酷炫的效果
I want the header tint color to be red and I
将 headerTintColor 设为 red
want the header style to have a background color of let's say green.
将 headerStyle 的 backgroundColor 设为 green
So now what's going to happen is you'll notice our Home View looks the exact same,
现在 你会发现主屏幕看起来完全一样
but when we go to Dashboard,
当时当我们在 iOS 和 Android 上
both on iOS, now on Android,
转到 Dashboard 时
you'll notice that our header is green with the color of red.
标题背景色变成绿色 字体是红色
So again, ReactNavigation is great because
ReactNavigation 非常强大
you can tweak basically anything that you need.
几乎可以设置任何效果
So we've looked at the TabNavigator which allows us to route between tabs,
我们学习了 TabNavigator 它使我们能够在标签页之间切换
we've looked at StackNavigator which allows us to
并且学习了 StackNavigator
drill deeper into our stack or into our route hierarchy.
它使我们能够转到深层次的路径层级
And last up is DrawerNavigator,
最后要讲的是 DrawerNavigator
which is going to allow us to have a drawer to navigate between items there.
它将提供一个抽屉式导航栏 使我们能够在不同的项目之间导航